Andy Gonçalves

Engineering Manager

∅ (+351) 93 502 44 10
⋈ andygoncalves.pt@gmail.com
in andygoncalves
in seekandystroy



General

Traits An enthusiastic and straightforward team player, I love to learn and hear about different points of view. A true believer in honest feedback and nurturing relationships.

Interests Leadership and management. Agile. Distributed systems and cloud computing.

Experience Architecture and implementation of the backend of cloud applications. Team leading. Implementation of all the stack levels of web applications. Some web development. Master thesis in cloud computing.

Life Biker, gamer, thai/kick boxer, keyboard enthusiast.

Professional Experience

2020-now Talkdesk, (2 months), Engineering Manager, Contact Center as a Service.

2020 **Talkdesk**, (5 months), Associate Engineering Manager, Contact Center as a Service. Managing two of the core teams of the product.

People management and delivery.

2016–2020 **Talkdesk**, (4 years), Software Engineer, Contact Center as a Service.

Developing, scrum mastering, and team leading.

Designing and developing the new core systems of the product, responsible for routing calls and other interactions. Maintaining the legacy call routing systems.

2013–2016 **Safira/KPMG**, (2 years, 5 months), Software Developer, IT for financial services. Full stack development of web applications, mobile web applications, and middlewares, for banks and insurance companies, using IBM technologies.

Education

2011–2013 Masters in Computer Science Engineering, Nova University, Lisbon, 17/20. 2 years MSc (Eng), focus on distributed systems. Thesis in cloud computing, grade of 18/20.

2012 **Teaching assistant**, Nova University, Lisbon, Introduction to Computers and Programming.

2008–2011 **Diploma in Computer Science Engineering**, Nova University, Lisbon, 15/20. 3 years BSc (Eng).

Technical Skills

General OO/functional programming, TDD, SOA and Microservices, event-driven architectures

Languages Ruby, Elixir (main ones). Java, Javascript, HTML5

DBs MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

Tools Git, SVN, Docker, Unix/Linux usage, LATEX

Last updated: 2020-09-18